[ eerie music ]
[ thunder rumbling ]
- [ thunder crashing ] - [ suspenseful music ]
[ thunder crashing ]
[ horn honks ]
Okay , go on through .
[ thunder crashing ]
All metal objects into the tray .
Purpose of visit ?
A patient pick up and transfer to Smith 's Grove .
You 're late .
Yeah , should be on the road .
Yeah , hell of a night , huh ?
- [ man ] Real charmer . - Yeah ,
- I 'll take you down there . - [ man ] All right .
- I 'll be right back . - Okay .
Yeah , first time here , huh ?
Hope it 's the last time .
Ya never get used to the faces , never .
[ distant screaming ]
Jesus .
Jesus ain 't got nothin ' to do with this place .
Come on .
- [ man grunting ] - [ gate sliding ]
Yeah , this is where society dumps it 's worst nightmares .
Yeah , the one you 're pickin ' up ,
just thinkin ' about him gives me the willies .
Yeah , a decade ago , Halloween night ,
he murdered 16 people , maybe more ,
tryin ' to get to his sister .
Nearly got her , too .
But his doctor , of all people , shot him six times .
Then he set him on fire .
Both of them nearly burned to death .
Yeah , I 'll be glad to see this one gone .
Oh , yes , indeedy .
[ elevator gate sliding ]
Welcome to Hell .
[ ominous music ]
- [ woman ] Doctor . - Yes .
[ woman ] The transfer personnel are here .
- [ doctor ] Smith 's Grove . - [ man ] Yes .
I 'm doctor Hoffman , medical administrator .
- Has he been prepped ? - Ready to go .
Who signs for him ?
I do .
Outside .
All right , check him out .
[ music continues ]
[ air hissing ]
[ suspenseful music ]
[ man ] I 'd assumed Dr. Loomis would be here .
Michael Myers is still his patient .
And if Loomis read memos , he 'd be here .
Fortunately his position is more ceremonial than medical .
And with Myers gone ,
my hope is that he 'll either transfer ,
retire ,
or die .
All right , let 's move him .
[ Halloween theme music ]
[ thunder crashing ]
- Watch it . - I got him .
I can safely say that Michael Myers
is now in your hands .
Yeah , well , I guess you 're happy to see him go ?
- Locked and loaded . - Then let 's roll .
Good night , doc .
Drive carefully .
[ suspenseful music ]
- [ car door shuts ] - [ engine starts ]
[ thunder crashing ]
Did Hoffman say anything about living relatives ?
Yeah , a niece living in his hometown .
- [ woman ] And ? - And she 's too young
to be his legal ward .
So the state owns him , hooray .
You know , I still don 't understand - -
[ intense music ]
[ both screaming ]
No !
[ thunder rumbling ]
[ dog whimpering ]
[ thunder crashing ]
Kiddo , it 's four in the morning .
I can 't sleep .
What is this , four nights in a row ?
You going for a record here ?
The seven-year-old insomniac 's hall of fame ?
Do you love me , Rachel ?
Ahh , serious questions tonight .
Of course I love you .
- Like a sister ? - Jamie , sometimes - -
Like a real sister ?
We 're not really sisters , Jamie .
But that doesn 't mean that I love you any less .
[ thunder crashing ]
Sure it does .
I know you miss your parents .
It hasn 't been that long .
It 's been 11 months .
Your mother used to baby-sit me when I was your age .
I 'll bet you didn 't know that .
You 're lucky .
I wish she could do the same for me .
Come on , Jamie , let 's go back to bed .
Come on , Sunday .
Sleep tight . We 'll have French toast for breakfast , okay ?
Nighty-night , come on , Sunday .
Night-night .
[ wind blowing ]
[ thunder rumbling ]
[ somber music ]
[ Jamie sobbing ]
[ thunder crashing ]
Now I lay me down to sleep ,
I pray the Lord my soul to keep .
If I should die before I wake ,
I pray the Lord my soul will take .
God bless Mr. and Mrs. Carruthers ,
God bless Rachel , God bless Sunday ,
God bless me ,
and God bless Mommy and Daddy in heaven .
Amen .
[ door creaking ]
[ thunder crashing ]
- [ intense music ] - [ Jamie screaming ]
[ Jamie crying ]
Help me ! Help me !
Help me , please , somebody , help me !
- Help me ! - [ thunder crashing ]
Help me .
- [ intense music ] - [ Jamie screaming ]
Jamie !
[ Jamie screaming ]
Oh , dear , God , it 's all right , sweetheart .
[ Jamie sobbing ]
A bad dream , that 's all .
It 's just a nasty old dream .
I 've got you .
You 're safe now , okay ?
[ man ] It 's okay .
It 's okay .
Shh , you 're gonna be just fine .
It 's okay , baby , you 're gonna be fine .
[ indistinct chattering , laughing ]
[ indistinct chattering ]
- [ telephone ringing ] - Damn it . Darlene .
[ tea kettle whistling ]
There 's a clean one in the laundry room ,
next to your blue slacks . Hello ?
[ man ] Honey , this tie 's got a spot on it .
I can 't wear this today , I 've got a 10 : 30 with Chuck .
[ Darlene ] Hang on , Mrs. Pierce .
Not that tie , on the other side .
That 's not the only thing you 're eating , Rachel .
Mom , I 'm on a diet .
You want an oinker for a daughter ?
- [ man ] Found it . - [ Darlene ] Sorry .
Do you suppose Susan can just bring her crutches ?
Oh , stupid question .
Tell her I hope she feels better .
Mm-hmm .
Susan 's father , she can 't baby-sit tonight .
- [ man ] Why not ? - Susan broke her ankle
last night at the ice rink .
- Rachel . - Mom , please .
You 'll have to watch Jamie tonight .
Not tonight , I 've got that date with Brady .
You know how important that is .
Well , tonight is very important
for your father and me .
Can 't you find somebody else ?
It 's too late .
What am I supposed to tell Brady ?
" Sorry , but I 've got to babysit my foster sister .
Go and have fun by yourself . "
It 's not exactly the end of the world for goodness sakes .
Sure , it is .
I think tonight Brady was ready to make a commitment .
But now my future relationship ,
my engagement , my marriage , my children ,
and your grandchildren have all been wiped out ,
because I have to babysit , oh joy .
I 'm sorry I ruined everything .
If I wasn 't here you could go out .
Oh .
[ man ] Good job , Rachel .
That little girl needs all the love
we can give her right now .
And all you can do is think about yourself .
[ knocking on door ]
[ Rachel ] Jamie ?
I 'm sorry , I didn 't mean it like that .
I can go out with Brady tomorrow night .
It 's no big deal .
But you wanted to go out tonight .
It 's my fault you can 't .
Well , tonight we 're going to do something better .
We 're going to go trick or treating .
I don 't want to .
It 's Halloween . I mean , don 't you want to get dressed up
in a really scary costume and get some candy ?
How ' bout this afternoon I pick you up from school
and we go get ice cream ?
Double scoops ?
Double scoops . Now let 's get some breakfast .
[ woman over PA ] Dr. Quinn , call 7402 .
Dr. Quinn , call 7402 .
- [ Loomis ] Why wasn 't I notified ? - About what ?
[ Loomis ] You know damn well about what .
You let them take it out of here .
For Christ 's sake , spare me the speech .
I 've listened to it for a decade .
The fact is , that Michael Myers
was a federal patient and a federal prisoner ,
therefore he is subject to federal law .
We 're not talking about any ordinary prisoner , Hoffman .
We are talking about evil on two legs .
[ scoffs ] I can see this is useless .
Do you know what today is ?
Do you know the date ?
Every day I look at myself in the mirror
and every day I remember .
Look at me , Hoffman .
Take a good look .
I don 't want anyone to have to live through that night again .
[ sighs ] I 've said this before ,
I think you 're the one who needs mental help .
[ telephone rings ]
Yes , Dr. Hoffman .
[ man chattering indistinctly on phone ]
[ ominous music ]
I see .
I see , thank you .
Apparently there was an accident
just south of Mill Creek , near the - -
- Loomis ! Loomis ! - [ door shuts ]
[ suspenseful music ]
[ police radio chattering ]
- [ car doors shut ] - [ Loomis ] Is that it ?
- Yes . - When did this happen ?
Sometime in the night . They probably lost the road in the storm
and came down the embankment , it happens .
- An accident ? - Yes , sir .
You believe that ?
Why shouldn 't I ?
How many people in the bus ?
Four , plus Myers .
How many bodies did you find ?
It 's hard to tell , they 're all chewed up .
Loomis , it 's over , leave it alone .
[ eerie music ]
He 's gone .
He was here , but he 's gone .
[ Hoffman ] Did you find any other bodies ?
[ officer ] Not yet , there 's a lot of ground to cover .
You won 't find him .
He 's done all this , now he 's escaped .
You don 't know that .
Michael could have been thrown from the bus .
I 've seen bodies thrown 50 , 60 feet from a crash site .
Even if by some miracle Michael is conscious ,
his - - his muscles would be totally useless .
Give the troopers a chance to search .
You 're talking about him as if he were a human being .
That part of him died years ago .
Now where are you going ?
Haddonfield .
It 's a four-hour drive .
You can reach me through the local police .
If you don 't find him in four hours ,
I 'm sure I will .
[ upbeat rock music ]
[ radio DJ ] And that was Big Billy - -
[ drill whirring ]
Hey , Gar , how about a 9 / 16 socket over here ?
[ suspenseful music ]
[ man gasping ]
Hey , hey , there , hello .
[ eerie music ]
[ country music playing on radio ]
Hello .
Is anybody here ?
Hello ?
Hello .
- [ chain rattling ] - [ gasping ]
[ intense music ]
Is anybody here ?
[ eerie music ]
[ dramatic music ]
God in heaven .
Michael ?
[ suspenseful music ]
Why now ?
- [ cane clatters ] - You waited 10 years .
I knew this day would come .
Don 't go to Haddonfield .
If you want another victim , take me .
But leave those people in peace .
Please , Michael .
Goddamn you !
[ gun firing ]
[ Halloween theme music ]
[ door slamming ]
Michael !
[ garage door smashing ]
[ gun firing ]
[ tires screeching ]
[ explosion booming ]
[ electricity crackling ]
[ school bell ringing ]
[ children chattering ]
Hey , Jamie , where 's your costume ?
Where 's your mask , or are you wearing it ?
I don 't need to wear a stupid costume .
That 's because every day is Halloween at Jamie 's house , right , Jamie ?
' Cause your uncle 's the boogeyman .
[ children ] Boogeyman , boogeyman .
Jamie 's uncle 's a boogeyman .
[ girl ] How come your mommy didn 't make you a costume , Jamie ?
How could she ? Her mom is dead .
[ boy ] Jamie 's mommy 's a mummy .
Stop it , okay , stop it !
[ children ] Jamie 's an orphan , Jamie 's an orphan .
Stop it , please , stop it !
Jamie 's uncle 's the boogeyman .
Jamie 's an orphan .
[ boy ] Every day is Halloween at Jamie 's house .
[ children ] Boogeyman , boogeyman , boogeyman , boogeyman .
[ girl ] How come your mommy
didn 't make you a costume ?
[ boy 2 ] How could she ? Her mom is dead .
- [ Jamie sobbing ] - [ dramatic music ]
You 're okay , you 're okay .
Jamie .
Jamie , are you okay ?
[ rock music playing on radio ]
You remember Lindsey , don 't you ?
- Hi , Jamie . - Yeah , hi .
You ready for some ice cream ?
I wanna go trick or treating , like the other kids .
But I thought you didn 't wanna go trick or treating .
You know , Rach , Discount Mart 's having a sale on Halloween costumes .
No , Brady 's workin ' there till six o 'clock today .
I know , don 't you wanna talk to him ?
I don 't wanna look pushy .
You won 't look pushy .
Well I don 't wanna come on too strong .
A guy hates a girl that comes on too strong .
Fragile egos and all of that .
You won 't come on too strong .
[ sighs ] Well , I don 't wanna seem too desperate or anything .
Face it , Rach , you are desperate .
We 're just going in and buy a costume for Jamie .
Perfectly legit .
I don 't know .
Well , do I drop you at the Discount Mart
or the Dairy Queen ?
Jamie ?
Discount Mart .
Can we get ice cream after ?
[ sighs ] You bet .
[ register beeping ]
Hey , Wade , why don 't you go ahead and make your move ?
[ Wade ] Don 't rush me , Brady .
Timing 's gotta be primo .
Yeah , well , money talks and bullshit walks ,
ya know what I mean .
[ boy ] Double or nothin ' you don 't ask Kelly out .
[ Brady ] All right , 10 bucks . Let 's see it .
[ boy ] He 's not gonna do it .
- Chicken . - [ boy ] Don 't forget , man .
She 's Sheriff Meeker 's daughter .
Her daddy don 't scare me .
[ Wade clearing throat ]
Fuck off , Wade .
[ chuckles ]
[ both snickering ]
[ children chattering ]
[ suspenseful music ]
- [ Lindsey ] Call me . - [ Rachel ] Okay , bye .
Rachel , what are you doin ' here ?
I thought I was supposed to pick you up .
Jamie needs a Halloween costume .
You do ? Okay , well , go down to aisle eight ,
we 've got the best costumes in the whole town .
- Come on , Rachel . - In a second .
We need to talk .
Okay , sure , what about ?
It 's about tonight .
[ rock music playing on radio ]
[ eerie music ]
[ suspenseful music ]
Rachel , I found the perfect costume , come see !
What ?
My parents ' babysitter canceled .
So ?
So , I have to watch Jamie tonight .
[ Brady sighs ]
Well , when did you find this out ?
- This morning . - Oh , you found out this morning ?
Well why didn 't you tell me before ?
I mean , it 's five o 'clock now , Rachel . Shit .
Don 't get angry .
I 'm not angry , it 's just ...
Can I come over after Jamie goes to sleep ?
My parents are gonna come home early tonight .
So ?
I don 't know , Brady .
Okay , I guess I 'll call ya later .
[ suspenseful music ]
[ Jamie screaming ]
[ mirror shattering ]
Jamie , what happened ?
It was the nightmare man .
- What ? - He 's coming to get me , Rachel .
You 're okay .
You probably saw a mask and it scared you .
At least you 're not cut .
Come on , let 's go home .
- Will she be okay ? - She 'll be fine .
[ suspenseful music ]
[ Loomis panting ]
[ girls cheering , laughing ]
[ girl ] Oh , look !
Hey !
Come on , old man , let 's go .
Come on , come on !
Hurry up , hurry up !
[ Loomis coughing ]
[ eerie music ]
[ man ] Get in here , old man .
I ain 't got ' til judgment day .
[ Loomis ] Thank you .
[ man ] Anything for a fellow pilgrim .
We 're all on a quest .
Sometimes we need help getting where we want to be .
[ sneezing ]
Reverend Jackson P. Sayer of Dumont County .
Pleased to make your acquaintance .
How far you going , Mr. Sayer ?
[ Jackson ] God 's country , promised land .
Where you heading , Mr. uh ...
Loomis , Haddonfield .
Car trouble ?
Sort of .
You 're a huntin ' it , ain 't ya ?
Yeah , you 're huntin ' it all right , just like me .
What are you hunting , Mr. Sayer ?
Apocalypse , end of the world , Armageddon .
It 's always got a face and a name .
I 've been huntin ' the bastard for 30 years , give or take .
Come close a time or two , too damn close !
You can 't kill damnation , mister .
It don 't die like a man dies .
I know that , Mr. Sayer .
Oh , you 're a pilgrim , all right .
I saw it on your face back there in the dust .
I saw it clear as breasts and blue suede shoes .
Would you like a drink ?
♪ Yes , we 'll gather at the river ♪
♪ The beautiful , beautiful river ♪
♪ Gather with the saints at the river ♪
- [ ominous music ] - [ indistinct chattering ]
Let 's do a light post . Light post . Let 's go .
- [ children laughing ] - Light post .
Let 's go .
That was fun ! Ha-ha !
[ children cheering ]
Okay , Jamie , we 're leaving .
- Where 's Rach ? - I don 't know .
[ Rachel ] Here I am !
- Come on , hon . - [ Darlene ] How do we look ?
You guys always look great .
We 'll be at the Fallbrooks ' .
The number 's next to the phone .
I know , and next to that is police , hospital , fire ,
and probably the National Guard .
I want you two to have fun tonight .
Make sure Jamie 's in bed by 9 : 30 .
[ Rachel ] You 're gonna be late . You don 't wanna blow your promotion .
[ Darlene ] Don 't make fun .
Tonight is the difference between vacations in Bermuda ,
or spending another two weeks with your grandmother
- in Cleveland . - [ Rachel ] So hurry up .
- [ Jamie ] Bye . - [ man ] See ya .
[ Rachel ] Good luck , Dad .
[ ominous music ]
Rachel , can I go get my costume on ?
- Yeah , hurry up . - Okay .
[ eerie music ]
[ rotary phone clicking ]
Is Brady there ?
He 's not back from work yet ?
Okay , well , when he comes in
could you tell him to drop by about eight ?
I should be home by then .
This is Rachel .
Okay , bye .
Come on , Jamie , you 're going to miss all the good candy .
[ suspenseful music ]
Come on , Jamie .
[ Jamie ] Come on , Rachel .
- [ Rachel ] Coming . - I thought you said you were ready .
[ Rachel ] I 'm ready , I 'm ready !
Okay , let 's go .
- [ suspenseful music ] - [ footsteps thudding ]
[ police radio chattering ]
Oh , uh , I need to speak with Sheriff Brackett .
Well , then you 'll have to travel about 3,000 miles south of here .
- What ? - Brackett retired , back in ' 81 .
He moved to St. Petersburg .
Oh , well , who 's the new sheriff ?
[ Meeker ] I am .
Ben Meeker .
Oh , Sheriff Meeker , my name is Doctor - -
Loomis .
Folks around here aren 't likely to forget your face .
At least not cops .
So , what brings you back here after 10 years ?
Michael Myers has escaped from Ridgemont .
He 's here in Haddonfield .
That 's impossible , Michael Myers is an invalid .
He 's here , Sheriff .
Why ?
10 years ago , he tried to kill Laurie Strode .
Now he wants her daughter .
You talkin ' about Jamie Lloyd ?
Wherever she is , that little child is in mortal danger .
Myers has been locked up since before she was born .
He 's never laid eyes on her .
Six bodies , sheriff , that 's what I 've seen !
Between here and Ridgemont , a filling station in flames !
I tell you , Michael Myers is here ,
in this town !
He 's here to kill that little girl
and anybody who gets in his way !
All right , Pierce , call the troopers
and check his story out .
And assuming what you say is true - -
It 's true , Sheriff !
Fine , all right , it is true .
The hell can we do to avoid a repeat of 10 years ago ?
Find this little girl , and get her someplace safe .
Call the local TV station .
Tell them to get people off the streets
and behind locked doors .
[ Pierce ] Can 't get long distance , Sheriff .
Operator says the lines are down .
All right , let 's go .
When he makes that call - -
All right , Pierce , do it .
Let 's check on this little girl .
- [ Jamie ] Thanks ! - [ Rachel ] Okay .
- Jamie , wait for me . - This is great , Rachel .
Come on !
[ children chattering ]
- [ Jamie ] Trick or treat ! - [ woman ] Oh , my !
What a cute little clown .
Let 's see what I have for ya .
- There ya are , sweetheart . - Thank you .
- [ Rachel ] Thank you . - You 're welcome , honey .
[ sighs ] Had enough ?
No way . Halloween 's great . Can we stay out all night ?
Forget it , kiddo , we 're home by eight o 'clock .
[ children chattering ]
[ girl ] Hey , guys , it 's Jamie .
That clown costume 's really cool .
- [ Jamie ] Really ? - [ boy ] Yeah .
[ suspenseful music ]
[ boy ] Hey , wanna go with us ?
- Go ahead . - Come on !
[ children chattering ]
[ doorbell ringing ]
[ children ] Trick or treat .
Hi , Rachel .
Hi .
Here ya go , little monster .
- [ child ] Thank you . - A little clown , there ya go .
- [ child 2 ] Thank you . - [ child 3 ] Trick or treat !
- Bye . - [ Brady ] Rachel !
- Rachel . - Brady .
Just a second .
Rachel , I got - - I got an expla - - wait , I - -
[ child ] Hey , Jamie , come on with us .
[ Rachel ] You don 't owe me anything , Brady .
- [ Jamie ] Okay . - [ child ] Come on ! Wait up !
[ Brady ] Well , would you hold on a second ?
[ Rachel ] Just leave me alone and let 's forget it .
No , you don 't understand .
I mean , you blow off our date at the last minute .
So you hop onto the next best thing ?
I thought you were different from other guys .
Oh , I 'm different , it 's just that ,
I just got pissed off , that 's all .
Oh , really ? Well , I 'll just let you get back
to little miss hot panties .
- Rachel ! - Jamie ?
[ Kelly ] Brady ?
Are you coming in or what ?
[ suspenseful music ]
Jamie !
Great , Rachel , just great .
By order of the sheriff 's office
all citizens of Haddonfield are asked to clear the streets .
[ man ] I made that payment nine days ago
and I still haven 't heard from the bastard .
Everybody shut up a goddamn minute .
Shut up !
[ reporter ] All businesses are asked to close
- as soon as possible - - - What 's all that shit about , Earl ?
[ reporter ] Stay tuned to this station for updates .
Not like ol ' Ben Meeker to do something like that .
Sure ain 't . Martians could land on Ben 's doorstep
and all he 'd do is spit once and get himself a shotgun .
Who ya callin ' ?
Police station , I ain 't closing down
without a good goddamn reason .
[ line ringing ]
Well ?
It just rings .
[ rock music playing on radio ]
Well , c 'mon .
Jackie , watch the register for me , hun .
[ Jackie ] You got it , Earl .
- What 's goin ' down ? - Where we goin ' , Earl ?
[ Earl ] We 're goin ' to Ben 's .
The phone never just rings at a police station .
- No way , no how . - [ man ] Goin ' to wake up the sheriff .
[ suspenseful music ]
[ indistinct chattering ]
[ eerie music ]
[ suspenseful music ]
- Something ? - He 's been here .
How do ya know ?
[ suspenseful music ]
This is startin ' to spook me , doc .
At least you 're not alone .
Logan , I want you to stay here , in case the family gets back .
[ Logan ] Right here , Ben .
You look sharp , you understand ?
No problem , Sheriff .
[ electricity buzzing ]
Hey you ! This is city property , no trespassing .
What , are you deaf ?
Don 't try that Halloween shit with me .
All right .
I 'm on the telephone to the police , right now .
And don 't you even think about leaving .
[ dramatic music ]
[ man screaming ]
- [ electricity sparking ] - [ screaming continues ]
[ indistinct chattering ]
[ man ] Come on , kids . I want you all in the car , right now .
[ children groaning , chattering ]
[ man ] Come on , I said move it . Now get in there .
[ car doors closing ]
[ Rachel ] Jamie !
[ suspenseful music ]
[ Rachel sighs ] Jamie .
[ twig crunching ]
[ Jamie ] Rachel , is that you ?
[ branches rustling ]
Is that you ?
[ suspenseful music ]
Jamie ?
Jamie !
[ twig breaking ]
[ sighing ]
Jamie .
[ Rachel panting ]
Jamie ?
[ suspenseful music ]
Oh , God !
Jamie .
Whoever you are ,
I have a big dog with me and he bites .
[ Rachel ] Jamie !
Where have you been ?
Don 't ever go off on your own at night again ,
okay ? Not ever .
[ car approaching ]
[ Meeker ] Rachel , Jamie , thank God .
- What 's going on ? - In the car , c 'mon , quick .
[ suspenseful music ]
[ car door shuts ]
[ dramatic music ]
Is that him ? Is that him ?
Yes .
Loomis .
Oh , Christ , doc .
Dear God .
Hey , don 't shoot !
[ boy laughing ]
Oh , that was great ! You thought it was me , didn 't you ?
Sheriff !
Get home , damn it , there 's a curfew .
I catch your ass , it 'll be a weekend in jail .
You all right , doc ?
C 'mon , we 'll get to the station . We 'll get these kids safe .
- [ Jamie gasping ] - Okay .
[ Meeker ] Station , this is 132 . Come in , Pierce .
Come in , Pierce .
[ suspenseful music ]
[ busy signal buzzing ]
Oh , Christ .
He wouldn 't have given up without a fight .
They didn 't know what they were fighting .
[ eerie music ]
How could a man do this , Loomis ?
Tell me .
It isn 't a man .
Then what is he ?
Tell me ! What the hell are we dealing with ?
Evil .
[ eerie music ]
[ cars approaching ]
Ben , what the Sam hell is goin ' on ?
Go on home , Earl , this is police business .
What the hell did this ?
Uh , looks like to me you 're out of business .
Now I want some answers .
I haven 't got the time or patience to argue with you .
Now go home to your families where you belong .
[ man ] You forget who 's payin ' your salary , Sheriff .
It was Michael Myers .
- [ men chattering ] - [ Loomis ] He 's come home to kill .
Let it be , Earl , let the police handle it .
Like the last time ?
How many people killed back then ? How many kids ?
[ man ] Al , here , lost his boy 10 years back .
Well , not this time , Ben , I 'll handle this my own way .
We 're gonna fry his ass .
- [ gun cocking ] - [ indistinct chattering ]
You son of a bitch , you just created a lynch mob .
You haven 't got a police force .
These men maybe the only defense you 've got .
- [ man ] Come on , let 's move it out . - [ man 2 ] Come on , guys , let 's go .
Let 's hunt this bastard .
God help us .
[ door shuts ]
132 , 132 .
This is 134 , over .
[ Meeker over radio ] This is 132 , over .
Ben , uh , I just heard about the station .
- [ suspenseful music ] - [ Meeker ] Now you get over to my house
and we 'll call the state boys from there .
[ Logan ] I 'll be there in five minutes .
[ engine starts ]
[ Darlene ] Honey , I don 't think they 're home .
- [ man ] How do you know they 're not home ? - [ Darlene ] ' Cause the lights are all out .
[ man ] I told ' em to be here by nine , it 's not 9 : 30 yet - -
[ Darlene ] C 'mon , let 's call the Carters .
[ man ] You call the Carters .
- [ Darlene ] Kids ? - [ man ] Rachel , Jamie ?
[ suspenseful music ]
- [ man ] There he is ! - [ banging on roof ]
I seen his face .
Right there , Al !
- Right there , in those bushes . - [ guns cocking ]
[ bushes rustling ]
[ guns firing ]
Come on .
Shit , Earl .
It 's Ted Hollister .
You dumb son of a bitch .
You said ya saw Myers .
[ fire crackling ]
[ Kelly moaning ]
Let 's go upstairs .
Hmm ? No , I think we 're doin ' just fine right here .
[ Kelly sighs ]
- Ooh , I think I 'm in heaven . - [ Kelly chuckles ]
Oh , Brady , oh , Brady .
[ car approaching ]
[ Brady ] Oh , shit .
Oh , it 's my dad !
Your dad ? Your dad !
God , if he catches us like this - -
- Oh , shit ! - ... he 's gonna skin you alive !
- What ? - For starters .
Oh , God .
- Oh God ! Come on , come on . - [ Brady ] We 're going , we 're going .
- Where 's that deputy ? - [ Meeker ] He 'll be here in a minute .
[ Meeker ] Rachel , take your sister upstairs ,
first door on the right .
[ Kelly ] Dad , what 's going on ?
Kelly , I want you to close and lock all the downstairs windows .
- [ Kelly ] Why ? - [ Meeker ] Just do it !
Where 's the radio ?
Right through the kitchen , you 'll see the basement stairs .
Brady , you know how to use a gun ?
Oh , yes , sir .
Think you can handle that ?
Um , yeah , you wanna tell me what 's happening ?
Yeah , when I have time . You got your riot gun ?
In the trunk of my squad . Go get it .
Take these .
Okay , you got a hammer and roofing nails
and I want ya up in the attic securing it so nobody can get in .
You know , if something 's happening , I should just go ahead
- and call my parents . - Just get up in the attic .
Oh , yeah . I catch you groping my daughter ,
I 'll use that shotgun on you , ya understand ?
[ suspenseful music ]
[ gun cocking ]
All right , get the outside shutters .
- What are we doin ' ? - Makin ' sure no one can get in here .
Isn 't all this a little paranoid ?
If you 'd seen that police station , you wouldn 't even ask .
[ knocking on door ]
Rach , you okay ?
We 've been better .
[ Brady ] What 's goin ' on ?
Michael Myers .
Who 's that ?
10 years ago , Halloween .
He 's Jamie 's uncle .
[ Jamie crying ]
The kids at school were right .
Um , I 'm gonna be outside ,
upstairs , in the attic .
[ Jamie crying ]
That 's all the windows , dad .
All right , good , good . Logan , I want you right here by the front door , okay .
This is the deadbolt key .
[ deadbolt latching ]
All right , we 're secure .
When I padlock the back door ,
this is the only way in and out of this house .
- You got that ? - Yeah , got it , Ben .
All right , hon , why don 't you go make us some coffee .
All right .
[ hammer tapping ]
Ow , shit !
[ wood creaking ]
[ suspenseful music ]
Hello ?
[ high pitched squeaking ]
Who 's there ?
[ high-pitched squeaking ]
[ sighing ]
Can we go home soon , Rachel ?
Real soon , Jamie . Now , shh .
- [ switch clicking ] - How 's it powered ?
Batteries .
I planned a generator for the house next week .
I wished I hadn 't waited .
This is squad , 790 , Haddonfield ,
broadcasting on a state police emergency frequency .
Can anyone hear me ?
[ static buzzing ]
[ static hissing ]
Damn it !
[ flames crackling ]
[ tea kettle whistling ]
[ ominous music ]
Everything all right ?
Jamie 's sleeping .
When can we go home ?
State police will be here soon .
Not long after that .
Don 't worry .
I 'm trying .
It won 't be long .
[ dramatic music ]
- [ static hissing ] - I hear someone .
[ man over radio ] Yeah , this is Frank Butte over in Tuckerville .
You 've got some kind of emergency ? Over .
Thank Christ . Yeah , this is Ben Meeker , sheriff over at Haddonfield .
Our phones and power lines are down
and we have a killer running loose in the street .
Michael Myers .
[ Frank over radio ] This some kind of Halloween prank ?
[ Meeker ] This is no joke .
We need those troopers , and we need ' em now .
[ Frank ] All right , I 'll get the troopers right away .
Hang on , I 'll need some information .
Not goin ' anywhere , Mr. Butte .
Rachel , is your sister all right ?
She 's fine .
Good .
Sheriff 's radioed for help , they 'll be here soon .
Hell of a night .
It 's not over yet .
Where you going ?
To the Carruthers ' house , that 's where Jamie lives .
That 's where he 'll go .
Leave Myers for the state boys .
The state police won 't know how to stop him .
- [ Logan ] Do you ? - Maybe nobody knows
how to stop him .
I 've got to try .
Are you looking for this ?
I didn 't know you and Brady had anything , okay ?
You knew , you just didn 't care .
He 's not married .
Besides , I 've got a right to do what 's best for me .
Don 't you mean what you do best ?
Wise up to what men want , Rachel .
Or Brady won 't be the last man you lose to another woman .
Have some coffee .
[ man over radio ] Over at Allen 's Gateway ,
shot Ted Hollister by mistake .
[ man 2 over radio ] Well , is he dead ?
[ man over radio ] Yeah , he 's dead .
Oh , Christ , is Earl Ford out there ?
- This is Ben Meeker . - [ static buzzes ]
Answer me , damn it .
Sheriff , what is going on out there ?
[ man 3 over radio ] Yeah , I 'll swing by with ya .
Get my brother , Charlie , maybe a couple buddies to join ya over there .
Now , Rachel , you stay by this radio .
The state boys will send word once they 're en route .
When that word comes , you go tell Deputy Logan .
- Okay . - Now , you understand ?
Uh-huh .
[ indistinct radio chatter ]
[ man 3 over radio ] You know where the hell Earl is at ?
[ man 4 over radio ] No , I haven 't heard from him , not in a while .
I 'll be down at the gateway .
I doubt I 'll be back before the troopers get here .
Maybe ya oughta wait here ' til they do .
Hey , I got a town full of beer bellies
runnin ' around in the dark with shotguns !
Who 's gonna be next ?
Somebody 's wife , somebody 's kid ?
[ gun cocking ]
I can 't stand by for that .
[ suspenseful music ]
[ car engine starting ]
[ tires screeching ]
Rachel ?
[ floorboard creaking ]
[ suspenseful music ]
I thought you might like some coffee .
Pretty boring out here .
Wish they 'd fix the power .
At least we 'd have some MTV while we wait for the cavalry .
[ intense music ]
[ Kelly gasping ]
[ Halloween theme music ]
[ wood cracking ]
[ music continues ]
[ static hissing ]
[ man over radio ] Haddonfield , we should have cars dispatched
in five minutes .
ETA , 35 minutes , over .
Uh , okay .
Great , we 'll be waiting .
[ man over radio ] Uh , 10-4 , over .
Uh , over and out .
[ static hissing ]
Deputy Logan ?
Deputy ?
[ suspenseful music ]
[ Rachel screaming ]
Jamie !
Oh , God .
[ suspenseful music ]
- What is goin ' on ? - I 've gotta find Jamie .
No , no , what we 've gotta do is get out of here right now .
- Not without Jamie . - Look !
Do you think she stands a chance ?
- She 's not dead . - No .
- Is there another key ? - I don 't know .
Get out of the way , get out of the way .
[ gun firing ]
Ah , it 's metal , goddamn it , it 's metal !
What does that mean ?
We 're trapped in this house .
[ both gasping ]
Jamie .
Oh , Rachel .
Rachel .
[ Rachel ] Brady !
Move back .
- [ Rachel ] Brady ! - No .
[ suspenseful music ]
Son of a bitch .
Shit !
- Brady , come with us ! - [ Brady ] Go !
Brady !
Get up there , Rachel !
Shit .
[ Rachel ] Brady !
- Get up there , Rachel ! - [ Rachel ] Brady , come with us .
- Go ! - Oh , Brady !
Go !
[ gunshot firing ]
[ Brady grunting ]
- Rachel , come on , come on ! - No ! No !
- Brady ! - [ Jamie ] Rachel , come on !
[ Brady groaning ]
[ Brady screaming ]
Leave us alone ! God , leave us alone !
Jamie !
[ objects clattering ]
[ both panting , whimpering ]
Go , go .
[ both whimpering ]
[ suspenseful music ]
[ Jamie ] Rachel .
Jamie , get down !
Get down !
[ glass shattering ]
Get on my back , Jamie !
Get on , hold on .
[ dogs barking in distance ]
[ glass crunching ]
[ Rachel panting ]
Hang on .
[ Rachel grunting ]
[ Jamie screaming ]
Grab on , Jamie .
[ tense music ]
[ Jamie screaming ]
I want you to get down to the chimney , Jamie .
- I can 't ! - Well , try , damn it .
[ Jamie screaming ] Rachel !
[ Rachel screaming ]
[ Rachel grunting ]
I 'm gonna lower you down , Jamie , okay ?
- [ Jamie ] Rachel . - I 've got you , come on .
Go down , now .
- Rachel . - I 've got you , Jamie .
[ Jamie whimpering ]
I 've got you , I 've got you .
[ Jamie screaming ]
[ Rachel screaming ]
[ Jamie whimpering ]
[ body thudding ]
[ Jamie panting , groaning ]
Oh , come alive , Rachel , please come alive !
Don 't be dead , you can 't be dead !
Come alive , Rachel !
[ Jamie crying ]
[ suspenseful music ]
[ Jamie screaming , crying ]
Help !
Somebody help me , please !
Help me !
Please , help me !
Please , somebody help me !
[ Jamie crying ]
[ intense music ]
What are you doing out here alone ?
Everybody 's dead , I just want to go home .
No , no , you can 't , I 've just been there .
That 's the first place he 'll look for you .
Where - - where 's the school house ?
The school house .
Where is the school house ?
- It 's over there . - Come on .
[ ominous music ]
[ Loomis ] Come , we 'll be safe there .
[ suspenseful music ]
[ gun firing ]
[ alarm ringing ]
We 'll hear some sirens soon .
Then we 'll be safe ?
Yeah .
You don 't believe that , do you ?
No .
[ Jamie crying ]
[ intense music ]
- [ Loomis grunts ] - [ glass shattering ]
[ sobbing ]
Please , somebody , help me .
No .
[ Jamie sobbing ]
[ Jamie screaming ]
[ suspenseful music ]
- [ intense music ] - [ Jamie gasping ]
[ school alarm ringing ]
In the school .
Pull over , Earl .
What 's goin ' on here ? We heard the alarm .
- [ Rachel ] He 's inside . - Jesus , where ?
In the school .
[ suspenseful music ]
[ man ] Let 's get this bastard .
[ Jamie ] No ! He 'll kill you , too .
We have to get out of Haddonfield .
The state police are on their way , let them handle it .
I don 't know about you , Earl , but that makes sense to me !
Let 's get the hell out !
You saw the police station , let the troopers have him .
That 's what they get paid for .
Screw it , let 's get outta here .
Al .
[ suspenseful music ]
Okay , everybody , listen up .
I 've got Rachel Carruthers and her sister in the truck .
I 'm taking them out of town , route 4-10 .
The state police are on their way .
You got that ?
- [ man over radio ] Got it , Earl . - [ Earl ] Okay , out .
[ police sirens blaring ]
[ somber music ]
There 's the cavalry .
- [ gun firing ] - [ sirens wailing ]
You comin ' outta Haddonfield ?
Yeah , Myers is in the elementary school .
We 're taking these kids to safety .
Okay , there 's a highway patrol sub station
about four miles down the highway .
You 'll see the turn off signs .
Now , we 've got officers on duty .
They 'll take care of you .
Thanks .
[ tires screeching ]
[ somber music ]
[ Earl ] It 's gonna be okay .
[ suspenseful music ]
[ man grunting , groaning ]
[ man groaning ]
[ glass shattering ]
- [ Jamie screaming ] - [ Earl groaning ]
[ Rachel screaming ]
[ Jamie screaming ]
[ Rachel grunting ]
[ tires screeching ]
[ Halloween theme music ]
[ Rachel gasping ]
[ Rachel screaming ]
[ tires screeching ]
Jamie !
[ Rachel screaming ]
- [ glass splintering ] - [ Rachel screaming ]
[ brakes screeching ]
[ suspenseful music ]
Die , you son of a bitch !
[ tires screeching ]
- [ car thudding ] - [ shouts ]
[ police sirens blaring ]
[ Rachel breathing heavily ]
[ Rachel ] Jamie , I want you to stay right here in the truck .
[ suspenseful music ]
[ sirens wailing ]
Sheriff Meeker , we killed him .
Calm down , calm down . Are you all right ? Are you all right ?
- Yes . I 'm fine . - Where 's Jamie ?
[ somber music ]
[ Meeker ] Jamie , get away !
Don 't touch him , Jamie !
[ suspenseful music ]
Get down !
[ guns firing ]
[ boards cracking ]
- Oh , babies . - [ Darlene sobbing ]
- It 's over . - Yes .
Michael Myers is in Hell .
Buried , where he belongs .
These kids aren 't likely to forget .
They 've survived this ordeal .
They 'll survive its memory .
[ Darlene ] I 'm going to take Jamie upstairs .
Stay with Rachel .
Come on , honey .
[ suspenseful music ]
[ music continues ]
[ Darlene screaming ]
No .
No !
[ Halloween theme music ]
[ Loomis ] No !
No !
No , no !
[ Loomis sobbing ]
No .
[ music continues ]
[ ominous music ]
[ Halloween theme music ]